Hi, Mrs. Ji.
季太太
Ms. Shi.
石小姐
I've altered the clothes
您送过来的衣服
you sent over.
我已经改好了
I heard you're in a hurry,
听说你着急穿
since I was passing by,
我今天正好顺路
I brought them to you.
就送过来了
Thank you.
好的 谢谢您
Something happened to Meng Duoci.
孟多慈出事了
Qiushi!
秋实
Xiang Yuansheng!
向远生
What are you doing here?
你怎么在这儿
Arranged by the Captain.
队长让我在这儿的
I'll keep a watch here.
我会守好这个路口
Don't worry.
放心吧
Be careful.
注意安全啊
Qiushi!
秋实
Wait a minute!
等一下
What's up?
有事啊
Where did you find this hairband?
这个发箍是哪里捡的
Just over there,
就在那边
near a trash can.
那个垃圾桶附近那儿
Thanks.
谢谢
Are you injured?
那个人有没有伤害到你
No.
没有
Gosh.
没事儿就好
Don't be afraid.
好 没事儿了
You're safe now.
没事儿了啊 没事儿了
Meng Duoci.
孟多慈
Excuse me, where did the patient just go?
护士 刚才那个病人呢
I didn't see.
我没看到
Yuansheng!
向警官
Your sister has been found.
你妹妹找着了
Is she alright?
她没事儿吧
She's fine.
没事儿
Keep others informed, please.
赶紧通知其他人吧
Alright.
好
Sir,
师傅
have you seen a girl
你有没有见到过
about this tall,
这么高的一个小女孩儿
with two braids?
扎着两个辫子
No.
没看见
Done?
找到了
Wait a minute!
等一下
Sir,
这位警官
how did you get hurt?
你怎么受伤了
Wait.
等一下
Do you need help?
你需要帮助吗
Stop there!
站住 你要再走的话
Or I'll blow my whistle!
我就吹警哨了
Which police station are you from?
请问你是哪个警察所的
Just around the corner.
前面拐个弯就到
Hold on tight.
您坐稳嘞
Help...
救
Captain.
队长
Has she been found?
小孩儿找到了
Inside.
找到 在里面呢
Is she okay?
没事吧
All good.
没事 没事
Where did you find her?
在哪儿找到的
In a trash can.
一个垃圾桶里
Are you alright?
没事吧
No worries.
没事儿
You have a sister?
你还有个妹妹
She's been living in Shanghai.
我妹妹一直住在上海
Hi,
小朋友
what's your name?
你叫什么名字
Li Qiushi.
黎秋实
And you...
那你
Qiushi!
秋实
Are you alright?
你没事儿吧
Did you get hurt?
有没有伤到哪儿啊
Ms. Shi,
石老师
I'm okay.
我没事儿
Yuansheng saved me.
是远生哥哥救了我
Thank you.
谢谢你向警官
Thank you all.
谢谢你们
Just doing our job.
我们应该的
I didn't expect you
但没想到石督察
to know Yuansheng's sister.
还认识向警官的妹妹
I found out not long ago that
我也是前两天才知道
Ms. Shi was my sister's French teacher.
她还教过我妹妹法语
You're learning German,
你学德语
and your sister's learning French?
你妹妹学法语
Is there a problem?
有什么问题吗
She's pretty impressive,
你妹妹挺厉害呀
even knew how to escape on her own.
还知道自己逃出来
Minmin taught me.
是珉敏姐姐教我的
Good for her!
珉敏行啊
Where's Minmin?
珉敏呢
Where is she?
我
I've...
对 我吹半天哨了
She'd have been back by now.
她应该回来了呀
Quickly!
快
Keep blowing!
接着吹
Don't go...
不许走
Ms. Shi,
石小姐
Qiushi...
秋实她
Leave her to me.
秋实交给我吧
You go find Miss Luo.
你们快去找骆警官
Your man
你的人
has been sent to the hospital.
我们已经送去医院了
He said this dagger was used by the killer.
他说这是凶手用的匕首
Yuansheng,
远生哥哥
you'll find
你一定会找到
Minmin,
珉敏姐姐的
won't you?
对不对
Don't worry.
放心吧
Minmin might be in danger.
我怕珉敏出危险
Let's search under the streetlights.
我们去路灯下找
Okay.
好
Minmin!
珉敏
Miss Luo!
骆警官
She's not here.
珉敏果然不在这儿
Minmin!
珉敏
Yuansheng!
向警官
Xiang Yuansheng!
向远生
Follow him!
鸿发跟上他
Yes, sir!
是
Erbai, come with me!
二白跟我来
Luo Minmin!
骆珉敏
Miss Luo!
骆警官
Minmin!
珉敏
Could this be
这会不会
Miss Luo's hat?
是骆警官的帽子
A baton.
警棍
Blood.
有血
Minmin...
珉敏 珉敏
Luo Minmin!
骆珉敏
Why is there still blood?
这怎么还有血
Could something bad have happened to her?
骆珉敏她不会出事儿吧
So much blood.
这么多血
Yuansheng!
向警官
Captain!
队长
There's
刚刚发现
blood on the truck!
那辆货车上有血
Yuansheng headed that way!
向远生往那边去了
Move!
走啊 走
Minmin!
珉敏
Hongfa, come help me!
来 鸿发来帮我
Come on!
鸿发来帮我
Hurry up!
过来
Erbai, support her head.
二白来 托着头
Easy.
轻一点
Okay, easy.
好 好 松
Drive!
开车
Go, drive!
开车去
Minmin...
珉敏
She won't die, right?
珉敏不会死吧
So much blood...
珉敏出这么多血
She will be okay,
珉敏不会有事儿吧
right?
珉敏
Who did this?
谁干的
I don't know!
我不知道
I really don't know!
我真的不知道啊
I just
我刚才
parked by the roadside
我把车停在那个路边
to deliver vegetables to a restaurant.
我就给酒楼装点儿菜
I didn't know
我车上什么时候
someone was
多了个人
in my truck!
我真的不知道啊
Captain!
队长
I had no idea!
我真的不知道
A button in Minmin's hand!
珉敏手里掉的扣子
Find all the clues
去找到跟扣子
related to this button!
所有相关的线索
Go! Go!
去 去
Erbai, ready?
二白好了吗
All set!
队长 着好了
Xiang Yuansheng,
向远生
I'm taking her to the hospital.
我先送她去医院
- Xiang Yuansheng! - Get up!
向远生 起来
C'mon,
向远生
go with me.
走啊
Bring her to the hospital now!
走啊 先送她去医院
Help!
大夫
Help!
大夫救人
Somebody help!
来人啊
Stretcher!
快把床推过来
Injuries to her head and legs!
头部 腿部都有伤
Unconscious for a while!
昏迷一段时间了
Emergency treatment!
快 马上抢救
Erbai, help.
二白 扶着
Slowly.
慢点儿 慢点儿
Minmin...
珉敏
hold up.
撑住啊 珉敏
Wait here!
家属请留步
Minmin...
珉敏
Come with me.
跟我进来
Why would the killer go to your house?
凶手为什么会去你家
He wasn't looking for me,
他不是去找我
but for Li Qiushi.
他是去找黎秋实
Tell me why.
他为什么去找黎秋实
Remember Mr. Meng
还记得孟家那对夫妇
has a daughter?
有一个女儿吗
Is she Meng Duoci?
黎秋实就是孟多慈
Yes.
对
Then,
那她是孟多慈
who are you?
你又是谁
Just a passerby.
算是一个过路人吧
I stumbled upon
在文华饭店
the murder at Van Hwa Hotel,
偶然遇见了那桩凶杀案
and upon her.
偶遇了孟多慈
But where's
证件呢
Xiang Yuansheng's credential?
向远生的证件呢
I'm entrusted by a friend.
我受一个重要朋友所托
Who is that?
哪个重要朋友
I can't say.
我不能说
I need to know now!
我现在必须要知道
I can't answer that!
我回答不了你这个问题
I made a promise to him!
这是我对他的承诺
What about Luo Minmin's promise
骆珉敏的承诺呢
and the Fourth Station's?
四所的承诺呢
I'm sorry.
对不起
When I decided
当我决定
to stay in Shanghai,
留在上海的时候
I thought it's
我以为这是
my own affair,
我一个人的决定
and I made my decision alone.
是我一个人的事儿
I was wrong.
但是我错了
The moment I stepped
当我踏进四所的
into the Fourth Station,
那一刻起
everyone there
这里的每一个人
got involved.
都被牵扯了进来
I just never thought
我只是没有想到
that you would be the ones
承担后果的会是你们
to bear the consequences.
会是骆珉敏
I assume that
我当你
you're right to keep her identity
保密黎秋实的身份
confidential.
是对的
For safety,
安全起见
you can keep it
你可以继续保密下去
until we catch the killer.
直到我们抓到凶手
I must catch
我一定要亲手
this bastard myself.
抓到这个狗崽子
Miss Luo...
骆警官
How is she?
骆警官怎么样
Hongfa,
鸿发
have you ever helped someone who's drunk?
你扶过喝醉酒的人吗
No matter how drunk they are,
他们就算喝得再多
you can
扶的时候
feel their bones holding them up.
也感觉有骨头撑着
But when I was holding Minmin,
我刚才扶珉敏
she felt like a sack of rice...
她就像个米口袋
collapsed.
彻底塌掉了
I was thinking,
我就想
she wouldn't slowly
她不会像米口袋一样
but surely
破个洞
leak away
就这么一点点
like rice,
一点点
would she?
就漏没了吧
I've been a cop for four years.
当警察四年了
This is the first time I've felt terrifying.
第一次感觉到后怕
Minmin...
珉敏
she will be okay.
珉敏没事儿
Stop crying.
咱都不哭了
She'll be alright.
没事儿
Which station are you from?
哪个分局的
Shiliupu Police Station.
十六铺分局
An order for Deputy Director Tan.
谭副局长让我来的
Guest inside.
副局长在接待客人
Please wait.
稍等
For how long?
大概多久
I'm not sure.
不清楚
Mr. Feng,
冯科长
you can go in now.
您可以进去了
It may not be
里面不是还有
convenient now.
别的客人吗
There's a regular visitor
那是我们
of Mr. Tan.
谭副局长的常客
You're
谭副局长说
allowed in.
你现在可以进去了
Good evening, Mr. Tan.
谭副局长
Sir,
先生
have some tea.
请用茶
I'll make you an introduction.
介绍一下吧
This is
这位是
our regular guest,
我们总局的老客人
Mr. Nakamura Naoki
弘济善堂的
from Hongji Benevolent Society.
里见直树先生
You should know that.
冯科长 应该知道
Of course.
当然
We send officers
我们分局
there every week
每周都会安排人
to keep order
去弘济善堂
to among the refugees.
维持难民秩序
If it weren't for Mr. Nakamura's
如果不是里见先生
generous distribution
广施善粥
of food and medicine,
又给他们看病发药
we'd
我们
need three times the effort
恐怕要花三倍的精力
to prevent them
才能防止那些难民
from causing trouble.
打砸抢闹事
It's a consensus.
这是局里的共识
So,
所以
Mr. Nakamura,
里见先生
you are currently
您现在是我们公安局
our most welcomed guest.
最受欢迎的客人
I learned compassion
因为我从中国人身上
from
学到了
the Chinese people.
悲悯之心
I know it's not easy for you
只是辛苦你们
to maintain the order.
帮忙维持秩序了
Thank you.
辛苦
It's our duty.
应该的
Hello, Mr. Feng,
特别是冯科长
It's the first time we've met.
今天第一次见面
Nice to meet you.
幸会
I am
这对我来说
greatly flattered.
确实有点儿突然
The man
刚刚我派去
I sent to 23 Wangyun Road
望云路二十三号
to find Meng Duoci
找孟多慈的人
encountered several policemen.
遇到了几名警察
Do you know
冯科长知道
what happened just now?
是怎么回事吗
23 Wangyun Road?
望云路二十三号
Mr. Nakamura received information
里见先生得到消息
that Meng Duoci is staying there.
知道孟多慈就住在那儿
His man
之前他派去的人
has already
本来已经
located her.
找到了那个女孩儿
But the sudden arrival of the police
但是突然来了几个警察
disrupted everything.
把事儿给搅乱了
Were they local patrol officers?
是那片辖区的巡警
No.
不
They arrested a man in the Concession before.
是法租界抓人的那几个
That's why
这也是我
I brought you here.
找你来总局的原因
Fourth Station again.
又是四所
Mr. Feng,
冯科长
how did they end up
他们怎么会出现在
at Meng Duoci's home?
孟多慈的家里呢
I'm sorry,
实在抱歉
I was not
我来之前
aware of this
并不知道
before I came here.
发生了这件事情
I'm gonna figure it out.
我马上查
Also,
另外
a female officer
有一名女警
saw my man.
看见了我的人
She could
这名女警恐怕会
become a problem.
成为一个麻烦
Handling this trouble
解决这个麻烦
is now up to you both.
就拜托二位了
I'm here on orders from
我奉陆军省之命
the Army Ministry to build a rear base,
来上海建设后方基地
and I appreciate
承蒙关照
your support so far.
一直顺利
I regard you both
我视二位为
as comrades in territory expansion.
开疆拓土的战友
Regarding Meng,
孟家这件事上
please continue to support us.
还请继续多多关照
Thank you.
拜托二位
Take care.
您走好
Again the Fourth Police Station!
又是第四警察所
I've transferred the murder case
我把孟家的案子
from them
从第四警察所
to you
调到十六铺分局
personally handle it.
让你亲自办
Yet they should
可结果他们
show up at Meng Duoci's home!
居然还出现在孟多慈家
Can't you manage
你就连区区一个警察所
just one police station?
都管不好吗
I'm going there now
我现在就去四所
to clarify all this.
把事情弄清楚
Come back!
回来
Go to the police hospital first.
先去警察医院
Nakamura's man
里见的人
injured a
把他们的一个女警
female officer.
打伤了
Go check
你去看看那个女警
what she's known.
到底知道多少
She definitely saw
她肯定看清楚
his face.
打她人的样子了
Is Nakamura
里见说她是个麻烦
suggesting we silence her?
意思是要灭口
We cannot do exactly as he said.
里见的话不能全听
Killing a police officer
杀一个警察
would bring us
对我们来说
too many complications.
有太多的麻烦
Nakamura might not consider this,
里见他肯定不会考虑
but we must.
但我们必须考虑
Go,
你去
understand the situation first.
先把情况摸清楚了再说
Got it.
好
Why the rush?
慌什么
Do you know
你知道
why I'm
我为什么
so close to Nakamura?
跟里见走那么近
Do you know what
你知道弘济善堂
the Society does?
是干什么的
Through its
里见直树
underground dealings,
通过弘济善堂
Nakamura Naoki has provided
地下的生意
substantial funds for the Army Ministry.
给陆军省提供巨额资金
His position there
所以他在陆军省的地位
is hence significant.
非同一般
The reason why I cooperated with him
我之所以愿意跟他合作
and released his goods
给他的货放行
is that if possible,
就是为了有一天
after the Japanese occupied Shanghai,
如果日本人占领了上海
you and I still have a place
我还能有一席之地
to live here.
包括你
So I don't want
所以我不希望
him storming
他再因为这种事儿
into my office
冲到我的办公室
over such issues again.
兴师问罪
Even if
就算
we didn't capture
我们真的没有抓到
Meng Duoci,
孟家那个女孩儿
Nakamura
里见应该
wouldn't turn against us, right?
也不至于翻脸吧
After all, he said
毕竟他说
we're comrades
我们是一起
in territory expansion.
开疆拓土的战友
Do you think
你觉得
he traded us for being part of his
他把事情交给我们做
secret organization
我们就是他
by asking us to do things for him?
秘密团体里的一份子
Or we have a closer,
和他的关系
stronger, and indispensable relationship
就比别人更亲密 坚固
with him as a result?
更不可或缺
You haven't realized yet
你不知道
that we've been in a situation
我们已经处在一个
beyond our control
无法控制
and mindset.
也无法看清楚的环境里
No one knows
谁也不知道历史
which direction history will take.
会朝哪个方向走
So
所以
don't be swayed
不要轻信
by empty rhetoric
那些廉价的话术
and false sense of belonging.
和虚假的归属感
What we can do
我们能做的
is to try the best
就是要尽最大的努力
to look out for ourselves.
为自己打算
Director.
所长
What's happening?
什么情况
Speak up!
说话 什么情况
How is she?
怎么样
She needs a drip!
快送去病房输上液
How?
算是脱离危险了
But it's hard to say
但什么时候能醒过来
when she'll wake up.
还不好说
Gosh.
你说说你啊
It's just a case.
不就是办个案子吗
Why risk your life for it?
这咋还不要命呢
What can I say about you?
说你们什么好
She's just a young girl...
这 这就是个小丫头呀
Calm down.
别激动
Minmin.
姐
Can you hear me?
听得到我说话吗 姐
Open your eyes for me, please.
睁开眼睛看看我好不好
Please.
你睁开眼睛看看我
How did this happen?
怎么会弄成这样
Does it hurt?
疼不疼啊 姐
Minmin?
疼不疼
Are you in pain?
痛不痛啊 姐
Dad and our brother
爸爸和哥哥都来了
are all here.
我们都来了
Wake up,
你睁开眼睛看看我们
please.
好不好
How did it get to this?
怎么会变成这样
Minmin, look at me.
姐 你看看我
Say something.
你跟我说句话吧
Didn't you always say that God
你不是说老天爷
cares you the most?
最照顾你的吗
Leave us alone.
都请出去
Minmin...
姐
Please.
出去
Mr. Luo, I'm sorry
叔叔 对不起
I didn't protect her well.
没有保护好她
Get out!
出去呀 出去
Are you in pain?
痛不痛啊 姐姐
Wake up.
你睁开眼睛看看我们
Didn't you say that God
你不是说老天爷
takes special care of you?
最照顾你了吗
Minmin...
姐姐
What do we do?
怎么办
Dad!
爸 怎么办啊
Minmin...
姐姐
Is she in pain?
她痛不痛
Are you in pain?
痛不痛